hello everyone I'd like to welcome you
大家好，我想欢迎您
all to this fall's this term's instance
所有到今年秋季的 这个 学期的 实例
of this course is officially either 15
这当然是正式要么15
to 13 from computer science or 18 to 13
从 计算机科学 13 或18至13中
from Electrical and Computer Engineering
从电子和计算机工程
but a large number the people enrolled
但大量的人报名
in this course are in one called 513
在这个过程中有一个叫513
which is for graduate students and to be
这是为研究生和要
totally honest you're not supposed to be
完全诚实的，你不应该是
here because you're supposed to watch
这里，因为你应该看
the videos the lectures by video later
视频讲座由视频后
but we're not checking any card so I
但我们没有 任何检查卡，所以我
don't really know who you are
真的不知道你是谁
Oh anyways this course is as you can see
哦， 反正 这当然是，你可以 看到
a very popular course on campus we have
在校园里非常流行的过程中，我们有
over 700 700 600 shouldn't exaggerate
超过700 700 600 不应夸大
students on campus enrolled in one of
在校学生就读于一个
those three versions of the course which
该课程的三个版本，其
if you think about a university of the
如果你想一想的一所大学
size of CMU that's like about five
CMU的大小就像大约五
percent of the total student population
学生总 人口 的 百分比
so we're very glad to have you here
所以我们很高兴 有你在这里
and this game is too high I think we
而本场比赛是太高了，我认为我们
overdid the game try that that's better
过火的游戏尝试那最好不过了
um so my name is Randy Bryant and my
嗯，所以 我的名字 是 兰迪·布赖恩特和我
co-instructor is Dave O'Halloran and
合作导师是戴维和奥哈洛伦
those names might be familiar if you
这些名字可能是，如果你熟悉
have been to the bookstore
一直到 书店
because the book was written by us and
因为本书是由 美国和
we actually wrote this book we started
我们 其实写这本书，我们开始
to 13 as a course in 1998 ah and I know
以13作为一门课程在1998年 啊，我知道
that your children them and all that
你的孩子他们和所有
stuff but out of response for a new type
的东西，但出来响应的新型
of course that you'll see today that
当然，你会看到 今天
sort of gives people a in-depth
那种给人 一种深入
understanding of systems but more from a
的系统，但是从更多的了解
high-level or programmers perspective
高级别或程序员透视
and we'll talk some about the philosophy
我们将讨论一些有关哲学
of the course later so this book has
该课程的后面所以这本书
used Co just came out its third edition
使用的共 刚出来第三版
last March and that's the required text
去年三月 ，这就是 所需要的文本
for the course and there is nothing you
该课程并没有什么 你
can do to avoid buying that book and
可以做，以避免购买这本书和
it's not because we're greedy actually
这不是因为我们是贪婪的实际
we take the money we get from royalty
我们把我们从版税得到的钱
for students in this course or any CMU
学生在这个过程中或任何CMU
course and we donate it to CMU
当然，我们捐赠给CMU
so we're not actually making any money
所以我们实际上并没有赚到钱
out of you buying the book but it's a
出你买的书，但它是一个
simple reality that the new version is
简单的事实是 ，新版本
different than the old we expect you to
比旧的 ，我们希望你不同
be using the new version there are no
要使用新版本有没有
electronic copies there are no pirated
电子副本没有盗版
versions so you basically have to buy
版本，所以你基本上要 购买
the book but and I don't really
这本书，但我真的不
apologize to that because I know you or
因为我知道你道歉，这或
your parents do somebody's paying a lot
你的父母别人的付出了很多
of money for you to be here and so the
钱让你 在这里等了
price of the book is really a relatively
这本书的价格真的 是 一个相对
small amount relative to that and this
相对于这一点，该少量
course by the way is not some courses
当然顺便说一下是不是有些课程
there's oh yeah this book you might want
还有的哦，是这本书，你可能想
to look at it once in a while but
看它曾经在 一段时间， 但
actually the course has nothing to do
实际过程无关
with it this course the book and the
它这门课程的书和
courts are one they're very tied
法院是一个他们非常绑
together there'll be parts of the book
在一起就会有图书的部分内容
that we don't go into all the details
我们不会进入 所有的细节
that are in the book sometimes but we
这是 在书中，但有时我们
expect you to be able to figure it out
希望你能 弄明白
and so really the course in the book are
所以真正的书当然是
tied together and they very much the the
绑在一起，他们非常多的
progress of the course the topics
该课程的主题 进展
covered how it's covered everything
覆盖它是如何覆盖了一切
about it is
它是
consistent with the book and we wrote
随书一致，我们写
the book because of the course think of
因为 该课程的书想到
them as course notes so and the reason
他们当然注意到这样和原因
why we are teaching this term by the way
为什么我们 的方式 教导 这个词
we haven't taught together in several
我们没有几个一起教
years but because this is the first roll
年，但因为 这 是 第一辊
out of this book and not only is it
出这本书的不仅 是它
being used here but it's actually used
这里所用，但它的实际使用
by about 250 schools around the world
由 世界 各地 的 约250所学校
and many of those people are also going
许多 那些人 也将会
through the same activities of teaching
通过 教学的同样活动
for it from this new edition for the
它从 对 这个新 版本
first time and so we wanted to make sure
第一次，所以我们希望确保
all the material for the course was sort
所有的课程材料是有点儿
of put in order and things because other
的整理和东西，因为其他
universities and other colleges use this
大学等高校使用
material of the supporting material
支撑材料的材料
we've developed so that's the course and
我们开发了，这样的过程和
today is the first election we're sort
今天是第一次选举 我们排序
of doing a tag team here I'll talk the
在这里做了一个标记队的，我会说话的
high level what the course is about what
高水平的课程是关于什么什么
the main themes are and Dave will talk
主要的主题是和戴夫将 讨论
more about the logistics so we refer the
更多关于物流，所以我们参考了
the saying we have when the very first
在说我们有当第一个
time I typed the number of this course
时间我打这门课程的数量
into a text editor I realized I have
到文本编辑器，我意识到 我有
typed those five digits many times in my
这些输入五位数多少次在我
career because it's the zip code of CMU
职业生涯，因为它是CMU的邮政编码
one five two one three so that's where
一个五两三种因此，这就是
we come up with the same so um there's a
我们拿出相同的，所以UM有一个
few things about this course for the
这个课程的几件事情
most part you know in your normal
您在正常知道 大部分
undergraduate curriculum when you've
当你本科课程
learned programming you've been very
学过编程 ，你已经 很
much separated from the realities of the
从的现实得多分离
Machine you just think about code just
机 你 想想代码只是
you put some text into some little box
你把一些 文字到 一些小盒子
somehow and outcomes of behavior that it
行为在某种程度上和结果，它
hopefully is what you intended the
希望是你想要的
program to do the purpose of this course
程序来做这个课程的目的
is to give you enough understanding of
是给你足够的 认识
what that box is doing when it executes
它执行时盒子是做
your code and through that to help you
你的代码，并通过帮助您
of become better at what you're trying
中成为更好的 你想要 什么
to do so some of the outcomes is there's
这样做的一些成果是有
really two types of outcomes from this
实际上是两个类型 的成果 ，从这个
course one is that if this is the only
当然一个是，如果这 是 唯一 的
systems course you ever take in your
你曾经参加课程的系统培训你的
whole life you will get useful material
一生一世，你会得到有用的材料
from it you will learn tools tricks
从中你将学习工具 的技巧
methods that will help you if you ever
方法，将帮助你，如果你曾经
are in involved in software development
在 从事软件开发
large-scale software engineering
大型软件工程
projects systems hardware design any
项目系统的硬件设计任何
aspect of computer technology this will
计算机技术 这个 意愿方面
help you be better at what you do you'll
帮助你更好地在你做什么 ，你会
understand what programs do how they
明白什么程序做他们如何
work what the machines that support them
什么工作的机器支持它们
do why sometimes they work really well
这样做为什么有时候他们的工作非常出色
and why sometimes they don't work so
为什么有时他们不工作，所以
well it also is intended as a sort of
以及它的目的还在于作为类似
stepping stone into a whole number of
敲门砖成整数
other courses at CMU that will give you
在CMU等课程，这将使你
more in-depth understanding of computer
计算机的更深入的了解
technology but our sort of specialized
技术，但我们有点专业
by topical area whether it's computer
通过局部区域无论是计算机
networking or operating systems or
网络或操作系统或
embedded systems where you'll take the
嵌入式系统在那里你会走
sort of ideas from this course and be
那种想法这门课程， 并
able to then learn in a somewhat
能够再稍微学习
narrower but deeper sense what's really
窄但更深层次的意义什么是真正的
going on and so it really is trying to
怎么回事，所以它真的是试图
serve those two goals of making you more
服务让 你 更加 的这两个目标
effective giving you useful ideas and
有效的为您提供有益的思路和
tools right away but also preparing you
工具马上还要准备 你
for later courses so one way we talk
供以后 的课程，让一个方式，我们 说话
about this instead of what why what kind
这个不是什么为什么什么样的
of stuff will you learn from this course
的东西， 你会从本课程学习
is to go through a series of what we
是要经过 一系列 的我们
call great realities places where sort
叫伟大的现实 地方排序
of computers meet up real-life computers
电脑满足了 现实生活中的电脑
get meet up against your expectations
得到满足了对你的期望
and maybe they're not quite the same so
也许他们是不太一样的，所以
one of them is and the first part of the
其中之一是和的 第一部分
course is going to take a fairly
当然是要采取一个相当
detailed look how numbers are
详细了解数字如何
represented in computers and you'll
电脑 为代表 ，你会
learn some things that are on one hand
学习一些东西，是一方面
surprising and another hand will start
令人惊讶和另一只手将启动
to make sense when you understand it
是 有道理的，当你了解它
better so a simple case is
更好 ，所以一个简单的例子是
for numbers I don't know when it was but
对于数字 我不知道什么时候 ， 也 只
it was probably in about eighth grade
它可能是 在大约 八年级
algebra that I learned that if you
代数， 我了解到，如果你
square a number it will be at least zero
方的数将是至少零
if it's not an imaginary number so a
如果它不是一个虚数，从而一
either an integer or a real number you'd
一个整数，或者您需要一个实数
expect to square it and it to be a
预计方 它，它是 一个
positive value or perhaps zero right and
正值或许零权
that's actually generally true with
这实际上一般与真
floats a representation of floating
漂浮漂浮的表示
point numbers but with integers or int
点的数字，但与整数或 INT
you know the computer representation of
你知道的计算机表示
integers it's not so clear so for
整数它不是那么清楚，所以对于
example if you square 40,000 on most
例如，如果你广场最40000
computers then you'll get whatever that
电脑，那么你会得到什么那
should be as you'd expect but what if
应该是因为你所期望的，但如果什么
you square 50,000 so you could do this
你方50000，所以你可以这样做
in your head but I actually built into
在你的脑袋 ，但 我居然建成
this laptop is a computer so I'm going
这台笔记本电脑是电脑所以我要去
to go ahead and use it
要继续使用它
we just size it a little bit
我们只是它的大小一点点
and use a tool which on UNIX systems is
并使用一个工具，它在UNIX 系统 上 是
called know what's going on before here
叫才 知道 这里 发生了什么
we are on Linux systems is called gdb
我们 在Linux系统上被称为GDB
but on a Macintosh OS X it's called L LD
但是在Macintosh OS X它称为 L LD
B but they're pretty much the same
B，而他们几乎相同
program you will get to know this
计划你会得到知道这
program really really well this terms so
节目真的真的好这个条款，以便
like I said a few square 40-thousand
就像我说的几平方 40万元
you'll get what you'd expect but let's
你会得到你所期望，但让我们
change this to 50,000 and you get a very
更改为50000，你会得到一个非常
peculiar number that doesn't look
奇特的数字，不看
anything like you'd expect 50,000
像你这样的事情会期望50000
squared to be and in fact it's negative
平方是，实际上它是负
and so that might just seem like well
所以这可能只是看起来好
there must be a mistake or something no
必须有 一个错误 或 没有 的东西
that that's just the way it is because
那这仅仅是因为路
this computer is expecting numbers to be
这台计算机被期待的数字是
represented as 32-bit values and the bit
表示为32位值和位
pattern that you get when you do this
当你这样做，你得到的图案
multiplication happens to be the
乘法 恰好是
representation of a negative number so
负数的表示，使得
that's a an example of where your normal
这是一个 在您正常的例子
expectations about integer arithmetic
有关整数运算的期望
may or may not hold on the other hand
可能会或可能不成立， 另一方面
there are some places like if I try to
有喜欢的，如果我尝试 一些地方
do the same thing multiplying 300 by 400
做400乘以300同样的事情
by 500 by 600 then all of a sudden I
500 600 然后突然 我 的
also get a number that clearly is not
还可以得到一个数字，显然不是
what you'd expect because the same thing
你所期望的，因为同样的事情是什么
has happened I've gotten an overflow it
已经发生了，我得到了 它 溢出
happens that it's overflowed to a value
发生， 它的溢出来的值
that's positive not negative but it
这是肯定的不是消极的，但它
still is obviously not the integer
仍然是明显不整
product of those four numbers on the
在这四个数字的产品
other hand one thing you'll find is even
另一方面一件事，你会发现，即使是
though this arithmetic is now
虽然这算术 现在 是
not a normal sort of integer arithmetic
不正常的那种整数运算
it actually has some well-behaved
它 实际上有一定的规矩
properties so for example if you look at
属性，以便例如，如果你看一下
what I've done is I just moved the 300
我所做的是我刚搬到300
around from the beginning of the product
从产品的周围之初
to the end of the product and so now if
该产品的末端，所以现在如果
you think about how associativity and
你想想如何关联 和
community works I'm basically
社区工作我基本上
multiplying these four numbers in a
乘以在这四个数字
different order but what you see is you
不同的顺序，但你看到的就是你
get the same funny-looking result no
得到同样看起来很有趣的结果，不
matter how you do it so what you can say
不管你 能说 什么你怎么做，所以
from this is integer arithmetic is
从这个是整数运算
commutative and associative so it obeys
可交换并且关联，因此它服从
some of the conventional mathematical
一些常规的数学
properties
性能
it just isn't what you'd expect it to be
它只是是不是你希望 它 是 什么
it's not a a normal sort of mathematical
这不是数学AA正常排序
integer arithmetic so the cartoon here
整数运算所以这里的卡通
shows an example that's a similar
表明这是一个类似的例子
possibility we get to it
可能性，我们开始吧
oh I guess it comes at the end I don't
哦， 我想它是在 年底 ，我不
know the next question is is a addition
知道下一个 问题是，是加法
associative right can you order the
联想的权利，你可以订购
numbers and then see probably might have
数字，然后 可能会看到可能有
figured bolted and the integer
想通 螺栓和 整数
arithmetic even though as this potential
算术即使是这种 潜力
for overflow it is associative and it's
溢出是关联的，并且它的
commutative too but for floats it's not
可交换太多，但 对于花车它不是
really quite the same because the range
真的很相同，因为范围
of values you can get in floating
值， 你可以在浮得到
pointers so extreme that some numbers
指针如此极端， 一些数字
kind of disappear on you so the example
你有种消失，因此例如
I'll show without having to use a
我会告诉无需使用
computer to do it is if you take a big
电脑 做它 ，如果你把一个大
number and subtract it from itself
数 和从自身减去它
you'll get zero so if you add that to
如果添加到 你会得到 这样的零
3.14 you'll get 3.14 but if you take
3.14 你会得到3.14，但如果你拿
those two numbers and you reorder the
这两个数字，你将重新排序
how you combine them so that that 3.14
你如何将它们结合起来，使得3.14
compared to a minus 10 to the 20th is so
相比零下10到20是这样
insignificant that that result gets
无意义的，这一结果得到
turned into minus 10 to the 20th and you
变成零下10至20日和你
add that to one 10 to the 20th and you
补充说 ， 一个 10至20日和你
end up with zero so it's not associative
结束了零 ，所以它不是联想
and so what you see is the both these
还等什么，你看到 的是这两个
number systems have some peculiarities
数字系统 有 一定的特殊性
and it all comes down to the fact that
而这一切都归结为一个事实，即
they use finite representations of
他们使用的有限交涉
things that are potentially infinite in
事情是在潜在的无限
their expanse and so there's some
其宽阔所以有一些
compromises in how those work and what
在如何将这些工作，哪些妥协
the compromise is you can overflow an
妥协 是可以溢出
integer and run out of room and in
整数和运行的空间和
floating point numbers you have roundoff
浮点数你有舍入
problems where you should have drop the
问题，你应该 有降
digits that are significant you can also
数字是显著你也可以
overflow floating points but the more
溢出浮点但更
common problem is round of so this is
常见的问题是圆的，所以这是
shown in this cartoon this idea of
在这部动画片 这个想法 所示
overflow of somebody counting sheep
有人数羊的溢出
which in the u.s. is in English language
这在美国是英语
at least a way to fall asleep and when
至少一种方式来入睡，当
he or she goes from 32,767 and then
他或她从 32,767，然后 进入
increment set by one gets minus 32,768
增量由一个设置得减32,768
and we'll see
我们会看到
exactly why that happens but basically
究竟为什么出现这种情况，但基本上
the numbers are going up to the largest
数字会达到最大
value can represent and then when it
值可表示 ，然后当它
goes one more it becomes a negative
去一个更高 时 ， 其 负
number so these are really important
号码所以这些都是非常 重要的
under things to understand I mean 90% of
根据事物要了解我的意思是90％的
the time maybe you can just get by
时间也许你可以得到由
writing programs and not worrying about
编写程序，而不是担心
whether your numbers are going to exceed
您的号码是否要 超过
their possible range but they sometimes
其可能的范围内，但他们有时
when this could be really important if
当这可能是真的，如果重要
you're like you know controlling a
你像你知道控制
rocket you really don't want the
火箭你真的不想要的
positive thrust to become negative or
积极推进成为负数或
something like that so you can see you
类似的东西 ，所以你 可以看到你
there this could be an important
这有可能是一个重要
consideration similarly there's
考虑 同样 有
well-known instances of security
安全的著名实例
vulnerabilities where somebody wrote
漏洞，其中有人写道：
code that sort of expected a positive
代码之类的预期正
number in some place and a clever person
在一些地方数量和聪明的人
figured out if I supply a negative
想通了，如果我提供一个负
number I can fool the system and get it
电话号码我可以骗过系统 ，并得到它
to do bad things so these are the kind
做坏事所以这些都是那种
of corner cases that you need to
角落的情况下，你需要
understand better if you're either
更好地理解，如果你要么
working in programs where it's really
在项目工作的地方真的
really important that it worked
真正重要的是，它 的工作
correctly or you're really worried about
正确或者你真的很担心
security vulnerabilities anytime you
安全漏洞，任何时候你
have possible four corner cases you have
有你有可能四个角情况
to understand these nuances better a
了解这些细微差别更好
similarly for floating-point if you're
同样的，如果你是 浮点
going to use floating-point for serious
要使用浮点严重
computation whether it's scientific
计算无论是科学的
research or for designing bridges or
研究或设计或桥梁
nuclear power plants or something you
核电站或你的东西
better understand what the
更好地了解什么
characteristics are so that's our first
特点是这样，这是 我们第一次
one and we'll spend a couple weeks
之一， 我们会花几个星期
talking about numbers and number of
谈到数字和数量
representations and their properties
陈述和它们的属性
here the second is we're going to spend
这里的第二个是我们要花费
a lot of time in this course learning
在这个 过程 中 学习 了很多 时间
about machine level programming meaning
关于机器语言的意义
what the instructions are that actually
什么样的指令， 实际上
get executed by the computer and that
获得由计算机和执行
can be described in assembly language
可以用汇编语言来描述
which is a text version of it or an
这是它或文本版本
object code which is the actual bit
目标代码这是实际的位
level binary encoding of instructions
的指令级二进制编码
and we'll learn a fair bit about that
我们将了解一个公平的位
and spend
花
amount of time seeing how code that you
的时间参观了解代码，您
write in aussie gets turned into machine
在澳大利亚写被变成机
code and how that gets executed on the
代码以及 如何获取 在执行
machine one thing I'll say is that
机器有一件事我要说 的 是 ，
historically courses like this would
历史上这样的课程，就
teach assembly code by having you write
通过使你写教汇编代码
programs in assembly that do various
在汇编程序，做各种
things not usually very interesting
事情通常 不会 很有趣
because it's a lot of work to write
因为它是一个大量的 工作，写
assembly program this course is much
汇编程序这当然是多少
more about taking the assembly code
更多关于采取汇编代码
that's been generated by a compiler a C
一个已经被 编译器中 生成
compiler and looking at it and
编译器，看着它，
understanding it that's a different set
了解它，这是一个不同的组
of skills than you need to write it on
技能 比你需要把 它写 在
your own and in particular we're going
你自己的，特别是我们要
to look at the language of of Intel
来 看看 英特尔的 语言
processors the most recent versions of
处理器最新的版本
them are called
他们被称为
x86 - 64 the 64-bit version of their
86 - 64 的 64位 版本 的
instruction set and one thing that's new
指令集和一件事是新的
in this course compared to previous ones
在这个过程比起以前 的
we used to teach 32-bit stuff this
我们曾经教过32位的东西这个
course is 64 bits all the time
当然是64位的所有时间
another one that we'll talk about a fair
另外一个，我们会谈论 公平
amount that is really fairly visible to
量实在是相当可见
programmers surprisingly visible is
程序员令人惊讶的是可见
aspects of the memory system so modern
因此现代存储系统的各个方面
computers have a very complex layered
计算机有一个非常复杂的分层
memory system to try and give you high
存储系统，试图给你 高
performance in high capacity at the same
在相同的性能在高容量
time and there's some results of that
时间还有的是一些成果
system that can mean that if you program
系统， 可以意味着 ，如果你的 程序
write a program well it might work
编写程序以及它可能工作
really well and if you don't it could
真的很好，如果你不知道它 可能
run very poorly because it's not making
运行非常差，因为它没有做
use of this hierarchical memory system
使用这种分层 存储系统
so and also there's a lot of bugs that
所以也有很多错误的 是
show up especially in C programs that
显示特别是在C程序是
have to do with memory referencing
有内存引用做
errors and so understanding what those
错误，所以理解什么是那些
errors are what their manifestation is
错误是他们的表现是什么
how to prevent them is a big part of the
如何防止他们是的一个重要组成部分
course so for example if I define a
当然所以，例如，如果我定义了一个
struct that contains two integer values
结构包含两个整数值
a in an array and a double precision
一个阵列中的 和双精度
floating point number D and if I
浮点数D和如果我
this function f UN you'll see what it
这个函数f UN你会看到什么
does is it's given an argument I and it
不被它给一个说法 我和它
sets the ice element of a to some
设定的冰元件在一定
strange-looking value so as you know I
奇怪的值，从而你知道我
should really only be either 0 or 1 with
真的只要是 与 0或 1
this code because that's the range of
这个代码，因为这是范围
possible values of this array a but we
此阵一的可能值，但我们
can try other things too so in
可以尝试其他的东西太多 所以在
particular if you run it on either one
特别是如果你在任何一个运行
or two you'll get what you'd expect that
或两个 你会得到你所期望的是什么
you assigned a 3.14 to element D of this
您分配了3.14的这个元素D
structure and when you read it back you
结构，当你读这回你
get the same thing and in fact but now
得到而 事实上，但现在 同样的事情
if I set a of two to this number all of
如果我设置为两到 所有 使用该 编号的
a sudden you'll see that my
突然间，你会看到我
floating-point number which seems to
这似乎浮点数
have nothing to do with a has changed
什么都没有做一个改变
and if I do that same thing with I equal
如果我做同样的事情， 与我平等
to three you'll see I get a number
三，你会看到我得到了一些
that's closer to two then to 3.14 and if
这是接近 两人随后 到3.14，如果
I keep going well nothing much happens
我一直很顺利没有什么发生
until I hit 6 and then the program
直到我打了6，然后程序
crashes so something interesting is
崩溃所以一些有趣的事情是
going on here at least something quirky
会在这里至少 古怪 的东西
is going on and the reason is again it
是怎么回事，原因 又 是
has to do with how data is laid out in
有数据是如何在布局做
memory and how its accessed and one of
内存以及其如何访问和一个
the features of C and C++ is it doesn't
C和C ++的特征是它不
do any bounds checking on a race it will
做任何边界上一场比赛它将检查
happily let you reference element number
愉快地让你参考单元号
5 million of a two element array and not
500 万的两个元件阵列的并且不
complain but the operating system might
抱怨，但操作系统可能
complain as it did here and it in this
抱怨，因为它没有在这里，它在这
particular structure and we'll see more
特殊的结构，我们将看到 更多的
about how structures are implemented and
有关如何结构和实现
weighed out but basically the two if
称量 但基本上这两个如果
each of these blocks in this vertical
每个在 此垂直 这些块中的
chain represents 4 bytes
链表示4个字节
and so the two elements of a each are 4
等等各两个元素是 4
bytes D is 8 bytes and then there's some
字节 D是 8个字节 ， 然后有一些
other stuff in the other bionda that's
在其他 bionda 这是其他的东西
not actually in the struct itself
实际上不是在结构本身
so you'll see that if I reference either
所以你会看到，如果我可以引用
a of 0 or a of 1 then I will just modify
一个0或1，然后，我将只需要修改
that array is designed but when I'm
该阵列的设计，但是当我
calling fun of 2 or front of 3 what I'm
打电话的2乐趣或前3我是什么
actually doing is altering the the bytes
实际上做的是改变字节
that encode this number D and that's why
该编码这个数D，这就是为什么
you saw the sort of funny numbers come
你看到的那种滑稽的数字来
out of it and as I go up at some point
出它和我去了在某些时候
when I hit 6 I'm modifying some state of
当我打了6我在 修改的一些状态
the program that it's using to kind of
，它的使用来样的程序
keep things organized most likely how it
为您整理 最 有可能如何
keeps track of of allocated memory and
保留的分配内存的跟踪和
that's causing the program to crash so
这是造成程序崩溃等等
this is a pretty good demonstration of a
这是 一个 相当不错的 示范
why programming can drive you crazy
为什么 编程可以让你发疯
because as you saw it doesn't do balance
因为 当你看到它不这样做平衡
checking so it's easy to write code that
检查所以很容易编写代码，
does invalid stuff it's also often the
确实无效的东西， 它往往也是
case that you'll cause some problem and
你会造成一些问题和情况
it has a sort of action a distance
它有一个排序操作的距离
feature that you can modify some think
功能，您可以修改一些思考
you're modifying some data structure and
您正在修改一些数据结构和
what you're doing because of the way
你正在做的 ， 因为什么样的方式
things are organized in memory you're
事情是在内存中组织 你
changing something totally unrelated
改变完全无关的东西
somewhere else in the program you'd
程序中某个位置 ，你想 别人
imagine they're not just one apart but
想象他们不只是一个，但除了
they're 10,000 apart and things might
他们除了万和事情都有可能
just run fine for hours days or weeks
只要运行罚款小时数天或数周
and then always say at some point that
然后总是在某一点说，
data that got corrupted a long time ago
这有一个很久以前被破坏的数据
gets accessed and something goes wrong
被访问和不顺心的事
so this can be some of the worst
所以这可能 是一些 最严重的
nightmare debugging nightmares that
噩梦调试恶梦说
exist on earth is to try and figure out
存在于地球 上 ，试图 找出
memory referencing herbs so this is
内存引用药材，所以这是
actually one argument not to program in
其实一个参数不是程序
C or C++ and it's a valid argument I'll
C 或C ++，这是一个 有效的参数 ，我会
admit but also as a
承认也可作为
person who's writing a lot of C
谁是写了很多的C人
programming you just get more
编程你只会得到更多的
experienced and you know at times that
经验丰富，你 知道，在 倍
you should actually put bounds checking
你应该居然把边界检查
in your own code and there's also tools
在自己的代码还有还有 工具
available that will help you sort of of
可用， 将帮助您 排序 的
bulletproof your code so that it will
防弹你的代码 ， 以便 它会
detect these kind of problems so it's
检测这些类型的问题， 所以它的
not like you have to change languages
不喜欢你必须改变语言
but it is a particular feature of these
但这些特定功能
languages and so understanding sort of
语言和这么理解的 排序
the Machine level representation of data
数据的机器级表示
structures and how they work is very
结构以及它们如何工作是非常
really makes a huge difference in your
真叫一个巨大的差异您
ability to deal with these kind of
处理 这些类型的能力
vulnerabilities and things of ulnar
漏洞和尺的东西
abilities by the way also from a
通过也从一个方式的能力
security perspective the the fourth sort
安全性角度来看， 第四排序
of theme we'll cover in the course is
主题我们将 在病程
getting performance out of programs
越来越表现出来的程序
other parts of the curriculum in CS do
在CS 课程的其他部分 做
much more emphasis on getting the right
更多的重点放在获得正确的
algorithm at the right data structure
算法在合适的数据结构
and that's really well and good it's
而这 真的很好，很好很
important stuff I don't deny it but they
重要的东西， 我不 否认这一点，但他们
some amount of the sort of low-level
那种低层次的一些量
optimization that you need to do that
你需要做的是优化
you need to understand what the system
您需要了解系统
does what makes it run well what makes
没有什么使得它运行良好是什么使
it run for way in order to be able to do
它的方式，以便运行能够做到
that kind of optimization so the example
那种 优化等等的例子
we like to use is these two functions do
我们喜欢用这两个函数 做
exactly the same thing in terms of their
正是 来讲 同样的 事情 ， 他们的
their behavior what they do is copy a
他们的行为，他们做的是副本
matrix or array from called source or
矩阵或从称为源阵列或
SRC to a destination DST they're both
SRC 到目的端DST他们俩是
size to be 2048 rows 2048 columns
尺寸为2048行2048列
two-dimensional arrays and you'll see
二维数组，你会看到
that the programs do the obvious thing
该节目做明显的事情
you have a nested pair of loops to do
你有一个嵌套的循环对的做
the row and column indices and you just
行和列的索引，你只要
copy from one source element to a
从一个源元素复制到
destination element the only thing
目标元素的唯一的事情
that's different you'll see is that the
这是不同的，你会看到 的 是 ，
two loops their nesting is different the
两个循环筑巢是不同的
nesting order is different in one case
嵌套顺序是在一种情况下不同
I'm going kind of row first
我首先要种行
going through all the rows and then the
经历所有的行， 然后
columns and the other is for any given
列，另一个是对于任何 给定
row I'm copying all the columns that's
行，我复制这 就是 所有 列
really the only difference between these
真的，这些的 唯一 区别
two programs but what you'll find if you
两个程序，但你会发现，如果你
run it on a typical system is that that
一个典型的 系统 上运行它是说
one is much faster than the other in
一个是 比其他 的 快很多
this particular machine we ran it on it
这个特殊的机器，我们跑了就可以了
was about close to 20 times difference
正要接近20倍 差异
in performance so something fishy is
在表现如此有鬼是
going on if the same program that
如果相同的程序去上
differs only in this seemingly
不同之处仅在 这看似
insignificant way a way that has no
微不足道的方式，有没有一种方法
effect whatsoever on its functionality
其功能 任何作用
can have this much performance
能有这么多的表现
difference and so to understand this you
差这么理解这一点，你
need to stare at the cover of the book
需要在书的封面去盯
because basically you're two different
因为基本上 你是两个不同的
points of this strange-looking picture
这个奇怪的图片点
that's on your book and since there's no
这是对你的书，因为没有
axes or labels on it it makes no sense
轴或者它的标签是没有 意义
whatsoever but it's there so what you
无论如何 但它的存在所以你
see is this picture shows four different
看到的是这 幅画显示了四个不同的
memory access patterns and I won't go
内存访问模式，我不会去
into the details of what the throughput
进入吞吐量 什么的细节
measured in megabytes per second on on a
在每秒兆字节上所测量的
basically a copying program was and
基本上是复制程序 是和
without going into the details what
没有进入细节什么
you'll see is these two functions sort
你将看到的是某种这两个函数
of sit at different points in this
的坐在这个不同点
memory access pattern the one that goes
内存访问模式就是那张在一个
through row by row is much better than
通过排排不过如此
the one that goes through column by
一 ， 通过柱由去
column and as a result you're getting a
列，因此你得到一个
lot better performance that it has to do
很多更好的性能，它必须做
with this memory hierarchy and what they
这种 存储层次以及他们
call the cache memories that you're
调用高速缓存存储器，你是
getting way better performance out of it
得到更好的方式表现出来 的
in case than the other so that's
在情况下比其他所以 这是
explains what the cover of the book is
介绍了书的封面是什么
about and we'll talk about it more later
关于多以后 ，我们会谈论 它
in the course and then a final part of
在使用过程中和然后的最后部分
the course talks more about not just
过程中更多地谈论不 只是
getting computers to run little programs
让电脑运行小程序
in isolation but getting computers that
在孤立的，而是让电脑即
talk to each other over networks and
互相交谈在网络和
implement services like web servers and
实现诸如网络服务器 和 服务
other functions like that which of
其它的功能和其它其中
course is where
当然在这里
most in the world of computing sits
大多数 计算机世界坐镇
today it's not just isolated machines
今天它不 只是孤立的机器
but computers that interact with each
但与每个互动电脑
other over the network they're embedded
其他在他们的嵌入式网络
controllers that are interacting with
是与交互控制器
the physical world
物理 世界
so really the the world of computers is
所以真正 计算机的世界
a much richer environment and will cover
更丰富的环境，将覆盖
at least some aspects of that in the
在中， 至少有一些方面
final part of this course so as I
这当然这样的最后一部分我
mentioned the other feature of this
提到 这 一点 其他 功能
course is it will get you ready for
当然是它会得到你准备好了
other systems courses you might take it
其他系统的课程，你可以 把它
CMU and here we listed actually a subset
CMU 在这里， 我们其实上市的一个子集
of the courses at the university that
在大学的课程，
require this course is a prerequisite
需要这当然是一个先决条件
and they're mostly in computer science
而且他们大多是在 计算机科学
and ECE but you'll see it's quite a
和ECE 但你会看到它是相当
range of of different courses and each
不同的课程的范围和各
of them builds on say one or multiple
他们的基础上说，一个或多个
aspects of the material you learn in the
材料方面，你 在学习
course so the reason why we make
当然，为什么我们做的原因
everyone take this course including
大家都走这条路，包括
incoming Master students is that all
进入 硕士生 是所有
these other courses at the University
在这些大学的 其他 课程
have come to rely on students being
来依靠对学生是
familiar and having done the work of two
熟悉和已经做的两个工作
thirteen or five thirteen as a
13， 五13作为
prerequisite and they can build on that
先决条件，他们可以建立对
material and sort of cover more ground
材料和排序的更多的地方
as a result rather than having to do
作为一个结果，而不是不得不做
what would otherwise be somewhat
否则将在一定程度上
remedial work on it and in fact one of
它和实际上的一个补救工作
the part of the genesis of this course
本课程 的起源的一部分
was the people who taught the operating
是谁教工作的人
system course a 410 sort of complained
系统过程中410排序的抱怨
that they were spending too much time at
，他们花费太多时间在
the beginning of the course talking
在课程开始 说话
about some very basics of machine
关于 机器的 一些 非常基本的
programming and and Dave and I said oh
编程和戴夫和 我说哦
well we can cover that so that was part
好，我们可以覆盖 所以这是部分
of what got this course started and as I
怎样得到这个过程开始和我
mentioned that the course has a sort of
提到，当然 有几分
perspective that's very different from
角度来看这是非常不同
traditional systems courses most systems
传统的系统课程，大多数系统
courses including that whole array saw
课程包括整个阵列看到
there were about how do I build some
有关于我如何建立一些
particular feature how do i implement an
特定的功能如何实现的
operating system how do I design a
操作系统我怎么设计
pipeline microprocessor
管道微处理器
and don't it's all important stuff to
不这是所有重要的东西
know we really want the people who are
知道我们 真正 想要 的 是谁 的 人
out there building operating systems and
那里的建筑操作系统和
designing microprocessors to have
设计微处理器有
learned how to do it on the other hand
学会了如何做到这一点 ， 另一方面
is a way to sort of get new into this
是一种将某种获得新进入这个
and get the introduction and get the
并得到引进，并获得
experience we find it more useful to
经验，我们发现它更有 用
take what we call a programmers
拿我们称之为程序员
perspective meaning understanding of
透视意义的理解
what you as a person who sits in front
你是谁坐在前面的人
of a computer screen and types code I
电脑屏幕 和类型的代码 我 的
need to know about that machine you're
需要了解这台机器你
typing code for in order to be effective
为了输入代码是有效的
at doing it as opposed to somebody who
在做 这件事，而不是别人谁
some day going to be designing the
有 一天将要 设计
actual machine itself so that by taking
实际机器本身 ，以便采取
that perspective it gives you sort of an
这个角度来看它可以让 你排序 的
understanding so now when you go off to
认识所以现在，当你走下车 来
implement it you'll actually know what
实现它你实际上就会知道
these features are and why it's
这些功能以及它为什么
important to implement them well but
落实得好很重要，但
also that by doing this programmers
同时，通过这样的程序员
perspective it lets you right away get
角度看， 它可以让你 马上得到
tools that you can use in other places
你可以在其他地方使用的工具
where you're writing programs are doing
在那里你写的程序在做
anything related to it and be more
任何有关它 和更
effective at that so this programmers
有效的，这么这个 程序员
perspective really gives this dual
透视真的让这双
benefit to it that we feel is very
受益于它，我们感到非常
useful and students have taken the
有用和学生都采取了
course in the past have expressed that
当然，在过去已经表示，
as well so as I mentioned the we have
也因此，正如我 所提到的，我们有
two instructors for the course
两名教官的课程
and they also happen to be authors and
他们也正好是作者和
the longest we've probably taught this
最长我们也许教会了这
course more than anyone else but it's
当然比任何人都人，但它的
also taught by other people on campus as
还教其他人在校园里为
well so what I'm going to do now is hand
舒服，所以我什么都现在要做的就是手
my pair of microphones over two days all
我对麦克风两天所有
right welcome good afternoon it's great
右欢迎大家下午好 这是伟大的
to see you my name is Dave Wilhelm Hren
看到你我的名字是达沃·威廉·伦
and I'm just delighted to have the
而我只是高兴有
opportunity to be one of your
机会是一个 你
instructors this term this course is one
教官这个学期 这门课程是一个
of the reason I'm so excited to be
的原因，我很高兴能成为
teaching this course I mean I just love
教授这门课程我的意思是我很喜欢
this course and
这门课
the real reason is the the opportunity
真正的原因是机会
of represents to have an impact on
代表有产生影响
people's lives we really believe that
人们的生活，我们真的相信
the material you learned this semester
材料你学习这学期
can help a really positive and
可以帮助一个非常积极的和
long-lasting impact on on your careers
对你的职业生涯长期影响
and it'll help you not only with your
它会帮助你不仅你
future classes but also future positions
未来的类，但也是未来位置
you have and I hear this from people all
你已经和我听到这个来自 人 都
all the time
每时每刻
former CMU students and students around
前CMU的学生和周围同学
the world to have taken the equivalent
世界上已经采取了相当的
of 213 at their schools
213在他们的学校
even a couple years ago we were
甚至在几年前我们
interviewing a faculty member finished
面试的教员完成
tenure-track faculty member who went to
谁去终身教授成员
did his undergrad at CMU and then went
做了他在CMU本科，然后去
off to Stanford got his PhD at Stanford
截止到斯坦福大学获得博士学位斯坦福
and was coming back to you know join the
并要回 你知道加盟
faculty and he told me that 213 changed
教师，他告诉我说，213 改变
his life in our interview and I don't
他在我们的采访生活，我不
know if he was trying to butter me up
知道他是想我马屁
but I I think I believe him he he said
但二想，我相信 他，他，他说
it changed his whole life in the sense
它在某种意义上改变了他的一生
that it gave him a research direction
这给了他的研究方向
you know he didn't really know what what
你知道他真的不知道什么什么
he knew it kind of like computer science
他知道这有点像计算机科学
but it didn't really know what direction
但它并没有真正知道什么方向
to go and and after he took to 13 he
去和后，他走上了 他13
knew they wanted to to do his word was
知道他们想要做他的话
life's work in systems now it was just
生活在系统方面的工作，现在这只是
remarkable right to come back and have
显着的 右回来，有
we ended up actually hiring him and he
我们最后居然雇用 他，他
told me that everybody in his lab at
告诉我，每个人都 在他的实验室在
Stanford all of the grad students had a
斯坦福大学所有研究生的有
copy of a book on their desk front and
一 本书上自己的办公桌 前拷贝和
they were from all over you know all
他们来自全国各地，你知道所有
different schools and so I mean I even I
不同的学校 ，所以我的意思是我连我自己
was in a bookstore in Beijing a couple
在北京一对夫妇书店
years ago right outside the PKU campus
年前外面的北大校园
and I was up on the fifth floor trying
我是上了 五楼试图
to see if I could find a copy of the
看看如果我能找到的一个副本
textbook and I found the English version
课本，我发现英文版本
in one aisle and then a couple aisles
在一个过道，然后一对夫妇的过道
over I found the Chinese version I was
在我发现中国版我
going through the Chinese version and
经历了中国版本
the sky tapped me on my shoulder and I
天空拍了拍我的肩膀，我
turned around he says oh man that that
一转身，他说，哦，那男人说
book is really good you should the
本书真的很好，你应该 的
English version is two aisles over
英文版本是在 两个通道
and I mean it just blew me away to be to
我的意思是，它只是把我吓倒了要到
be in the head of someone like halfway
在 有人喜欢半途而废 的头
around the world it was just that it was
在世界各地， 这 只是 它是
just one of those moments and so I'm I'm
只是 这样的 时刻 之一 ，所以我我
not trying to boast I'm just trying what
不是要夸我只是想什么
I want I want to give you the sense of
我想我想给你的感觉
what it what an opportunity this course
什么什么机会 本课程
represents for for Randi and I to to
代表对兰迪和 我 对
have what we hope will be a really
有什么我们希望这将是 一个非常
positive impact on on your lives so let
对你的生活，让我们积极影响
me we have kind of a kind of a funny
我，我们有一种一种滑稽的
organization for the course to it in
组织 在 使用过程 中 它
response to that just that the
针对这一刚才说的
tremendous demand we have we found that
巨大的需求，我们有我们发现，
we have for it so there's there's
我们有这么有有
actually three course numbers but it's
实际上有三个横列数 ，但它
all the same course okay it's identical
所有相同的课程还好这是 相同的
course 513 15 513 is for our master
当然513 15 513是我们的主人
students and the 513 513 doesn't have a
学生和513 513不具有
formal lecture so there's no seats
正式讲课所以没有座位
assigned to it
分配给它
instead we'll videotape the lectures and
相反，我们将录像带讲座和
we'll make those available on the course
我们会让球场上的那些可用
web web page for our for our graduate
网站的网页为 我们为我们的毕业生
students and the reason we do this is
学生和我们这样做的原因 是
just because in the past well we we
只是因为在过去的 好，我们大家
didn't have enough seats for everyone
没有给大家足够的席位
and there would be cases where there
并且会有存在的情况下
might be a hundred 150
可能是一百150
Master students on the waitlist they
硕士生在他们等候名单
wouldn't be able to get into the course
将无法 进入课程
and we we didn't really want that
而 我们，我们真的不 希望出现这种情况
because they need this course for to
因为他们需要这些课程来
take other courses so that's the reason
采取其他课程，这就是原因
why we have this this sort of does not
为什么 我们有这样这种 不
meet version of 213 is 513 because we
213相遇的版本是513，因为我们
can admit as many all the master's
可以承认许多众高手的
students that that need to take the
学生这一需求走
course now 15 to 13 and 18 to 13 or are
当然，现在15至13和18至13 或者
for undergraduates in computer science
本科计算机科学
and ECE respectively okay and the
和ECE 分别没关系和
undergraduates will go to lectures and
大学生会去讲课和
recitations okay in person graduate
朗诵的人 毕业 好吗
students will watch videotapes of those
学生将观看那些录影带
but otherwise yes
但在其他方面是
for those videotapes will they be
对于那些录像带才具
available Kamal yeah we're making them
可卡迈勒是的，我们正在做他们
available to everyone actually sorry and
提供给大家真正难过，
lecture slides as well everything is
演讲稿以及一切
available on the course web page so so
现有的课程 网页 上 ，以便 使
you'll be doing the all of students will
你会做的所有学生的意志
have equal access to office hours the
有 办公时间 平等机会
staff mailing list and everybody does
工作人员邮件列表和每个人都这样
the same labs and the same exams okay so
同样的实验室 和同一个考试 好了，
it's just a question it's just a matter
它只是一个问题，它只是 一个 问题
of whether you're good a lecture in
是否你很好的演讲
person or if you're watching on video in
人，或者你在观看视频
fact if you know since it's available to
事实上，如果你知道，因为它提供给
everybody if you miss lecture it'll be
大家如果你错过了演讲它会
there on the web page and you can catch
有在网页上， 您可以看看
up which I know you'll probably do
其中多达我知道你可能会做
actually I know most of you will never
其实我知道你们中的大多数永远不会
miss class right but the few of you who
缺课的权利，但为数不多的你是谁
do you'll be able to watch the video
你就可以 观看 视频
okay all right this is the one part I
没事没事，这是一个部分我
list the part I hate
列出我最讨厌的部分
I love teaching that this is this is the
我热爱教学， 这是这是
one part teaching that none of us really
一部分教导说我们没有真的
like but we have to talk about it and
喜欢，但我们不得不说说 它和
that's academic integrity if you're new
这是学术诚信，如果你是新的
on campus coming from a international
在校园里从国际来
school if you're an international
学校如果你是一个国际
student new on campus there might be
学生在 校园里 新的 可能存在
different notions of academic integrity
学术诚信的不同的概念
and different notions of cheating at
和不同的概念作弊的在
your undergraduate school or your old
你的本科学校或者你的老
school so if you're new on campus pay
学校，所以如果你在校园里新的 工资
very close attention to this because at
非常密切地关注这一点 ，因为在
Carnegie Mellon we take academic
卡耐基梅隆大学，我们采取学术
integrity very seriously okay it's not a
诚信很认真 还好 这不是一个
wink wink nod nod we're very serious
眼色点头点头，我们 很认真
about it
它
and we want you we want everybody doing
我们希望你，我们希望每个人都做
their own work to preserve the integrity
自己的工作保存完整
of the courses so what exactly is
该课程的那么到底是什么
cheating so if you share code with
欺骗，所以如果你有共享代码
anybody either copying
无论任何人复制
retyping looking at somebody's code like
重新输入看着别人的代码一样
if you look at somebody's code on the
如果你看一下别人的对码
screen or if you give somebody a file
屏幕或者如果你给了别人的文件
all of those all of those examples of
所有这些所有的 这些例子 的
sharing are cheating if if you describe
如果在共享，如果你形容在作弊
your code like line by line to somebody
你的代码像一行一行地人
that's cheating
那是作弊
if you coach somebody line by line
如果教练一行有人线
searching the web for solutions just the
在 网上搜索解决方案 只是
act of searching is cheating and this is
搜索的行为是一种欺骗行为 ， 这是
a this is a real problem for us in
一，这是对我们的一个现实问题
particular because the course is offered
特别是因为该课程是提供
all around the world and people either
所有的世界和周围的人无论是
maliciously or or sometimes just they're
恶意或或有时只是他们
proud of their work and they post it you
他们的 工作感到自豪，他们张贴您
know for employers on like public github
知道像公共GitHub的雇主
sites so it's it might be tempting to to
网站因此它可能是很有诱惑力的，以
search for these solutions but even the
寻找这些解决方案，但即使是
act of searching is cheating and
搜索的行为是一种欺骗行为，并
definitely if you find some a solution
绝对，如果你找到了一些解决方案
in and use it
并使用它
that's cheating even if you modify it
这就是即使你修改作弊
afterwards and I just want you to
后来， 我只是想让你
remember I can I know how to use Google
记得我 ，我可以知道如何使用 谷歌
just as well as anybody else right so I
只是以及其他人的权利，所以 我
I can search for solutions too so
我可以搜索解决方案，也因此
copying code you know you might be
复制代码你知道你可能会
tempted you might be tempted to copy
动心你可能会复制
code from someone who took the class you
从别人谁了类代码你
know in a previous semester don't do it
知道一前一学期 不这样做
that's that's cheating - now what's not
这是一个的欺骗-现在什么 不
cheating so you can you can help each
欺骗，所以你可以，你可以互相帮助
other use tools you know somebody's
你知道其他用途工具的人
having trouble using gdb or you know
遇到问题用gdb或者你知道
they have questions about how to run use
他们对 如何运行 使用 的问题
a text editor that stuff's all great you
一个文本 编辑器 这些东西全都是很好的你
can help each other out using the tools
可以互相帮助 使用工具
how to log into the shark machines all
如何登录到鲨鱼机的所有
of that kind of stuff and you can help
这种东西的，你可以帮助
you can discuss sort of high-level
你可以讨论这类高层次的
design issues and that's probably a good
设计问题，并且可能是一个好
idea yes
想法是
yeah yeah did you take it a previous
是啊是啊你把它前面
semester oh okay yeah the question was
学期哦， 没关系啊，问题 是
if you took it in a previous semester
如果你把它在 上 学期
can use your your work and the answer is
可以使用你的工作和答案
yes so it you can also talk to each
是的，因此也可以 互相交谈
other about high level you know design
其他有关高层你知道设计
issues you know how are you are using an
你知道你是如何使用 的问题
explicit list or using a segregated list
显式列表或使用隔离列表
for your Malik lab okay that kind of
您马利克实验室 好吗之类 的
stuff is is is okay okay high level okay
东西是是是还好还好高水平好吗
low level not okay and basically what we
低水平不行的，基本上 我们
want you to write your own code this is
要你编写自己的代码，这是
not you know it's kind of a cut and
你不知道这是怎样的一个切出
paste world these days right you look
贴上世界这几天对你看
stuff up on Google's Stack Overflow you
东西了对谷歌的堆栈溢出你
cut and paste it but that's not that's
剪切和粘贴，但，这不是那
not the way we do it here we want you to
我们不这样做 来这里 的路上 ，我们希望你能
do the work yourself we want you to
自己做的工作，我们希望你能
enjoy the experience of figuring things
享受盘算的事情经验
out and learning how to solve problems
并学习如何解决问题
now the consequences for cheating
现在作弊的后果
there's a single sanction if you're
还有，如果你是一个单一的制裁
caught cheating you'll you'll be
作弊被抓，你会你会
expelled from the course with an R
从过程排出用的R
there's no exceptions all right if you
有没有例外没事 ，如果你
drop the course we'll just reinstate you
下降过程中，我们将只恢复你
and then flunk you it's really a it's a
然后不及格，你这真是一个 它是一个
very serious very serious penalty
很严重很 严重的处罚
because we just take it we take it so
因为我们只是把它我们就这么
seriously at at sub and it's just it's
认真处子，它只是它的
just something we don't want you to do
有些事是我们不希望你 做
we have amazing tools to detect code
我们有惊人的工具检测代码
plagiarism we have amazing tools to
抄袭我们有惊人的工具
detect plagiarism that are that are
检测抄袭是是
resilient to renaming reformatting they
抵御重命名他们重新格式化
operate at a very deep syntactic level
在一个很深的句法层面操作
and so just please please don't do it we
所以只是请请不这样做，我们
have I think 18 TAS will have office
有，我认为18个TAS将有办公
hours almost every day of the week
几乎每一个小时星期几
there's plenty of opportunities and ways
有大量的机会和途径
to get help start early if you get stuck
得到帮助启动早，如果你被卡住
start early enough so that you get stuck
开始足够早，让你卡住
you can go ask for help we have the
你 可以去寻求帮助 ，我们有
automatic extensions built-in if you
自动扩展内置如果您
need more time I'll talk about that
需要更多的时间，我会谈论
later form of grace days but please
宽限日期，但 后来表格 ，请
please whatever you do don't cheat it's
请，不管你做不作弊是
just tragic when it happens last last
只是悲剧，当它发生最后的最后
fall 25 students were expelled from the
秋天25名学生从开除
course some were expelled from the
当然有些人从开除
university because it was a second
大学，因为 它是一个第二
offense many were sent home I talked to
进攻许多被送回家 我跟
students who were like the only person
学生谁是一样的唯一的人
in their family to go to college the
在他们的家庭去上大学了
only person in their village to go to
唯一的人在他们的村庄 去
college and they were going home without
大学， 他们 去家里没有
without a degree and it's just tragic
没有学位的，它只是悲剧
it's just so please please please don't
它只是所以请请 请不要
do it do your own work and it'll be a
做到这一点做自己的 工作 ，这将是一个
wonderful experience
精彩体验
Randy mentioned the the textbook is
兰迪提到的 教科书
computer systems the programmers
计算机系统程序员
perspective third edition you can
你的角度第三版能
there's a whole bunch of supporting
有支持一大堆
material on the on the books website at
材质上的书网站上
CFA PT dot C s CMU edu and as Randy
CFA PT点（C S）CMU edu和 兰迪
mentioned this this book really matters
提到这本书真的很重要
for the course because actually the book
该课程，因为 实际上这本书
came out of the course right so the book
出来的当然权利，使书
is the course of course that's the book
当然这 本书的过程中
on and so it'll it'll really help you
并因此它会它会真正帮助你
love it the labs that we do come
喜欢它的实验室，我们做出来
directly from material that we discuss
直接从我们所 讨论 的材料
in the book so what I would encourage
在 书中所以我会 鼓励
all of you to do and I'm not sure if
大家做的，我不知道，如果
anybody has ever taken this advice but I
有人曾经 采取了这一建议，但我
say it every year anyway because I
说它每年反正因为我
believe it but I think a really good
相信它，但我觉得一个 真正好的
strategy for studying and preparing for
战略 研究和准备
this course would be to read each
这当然会读取每个
chapter three times okay read it three
章三次好读了三份
times work the practice problem so we
次工作实践中的问题，所以我们
have littered throughout the book or
已经散落在全书或
practice problems with solutions at the
实践问题的解决方案
end of the the end of the chapter and
本章结束的结束，
these practice problems are like little
这些实际问题都像小
sort of bite-size morsels just to kind
那种一口大小的点点滴滴只是来样
of just to kind of check your kind of
只是为了一种检查你这样的
sanity check of your understanding of
你的理解完整性检查
the material so I think if you've read
材料，所以我想，如果你读过
this if you read the book
这个，如果你读的书
each chapter three times and work the
每个章节三次工作
practice problems you it that would be
实践中的问题，你认为会
an excellent way to go through the
一个很好的方式去通过
semester and prepare the other book we
学期和准备其他的书我们
use is the Colonel Hannon Richie's
使用的是上校 汉农·里奇 的
classic C programming book I think this
经典的C语言编程的书， 我觉得这
is still this was written a long time
还是这被写了 很长一段时间
ago it's still the best book around I
以前， 它仍然是 围绕我的最好的书
think for C it's a it's a beautiful
认为对 C这是 一个这是一个美丽
example of technical writing it was one
例如 技术写作 是一个
of the inspirations I used when I was
的灵感 我用时，我是
writing the book you know I tried to
写这本书，你知道我试着
find that same clarity and precision
中找到相同的清晰度和精确度
that they that they turn hand and ricci
他们说他们把 的手，利玛窦
have in their book so this is a this is
在他们的著作，所以这是一个这是
a really good book I mean this is kind
一个 真正好的书，我的意思是，这是一种
of book it's a reference but it's a kind
书这是一个 参考 ，但它是一种
of book you can just read from beginning
本书你可以 从阅读开始
to end and get a really good
结束并得到一个非常 好的
understanding of
了解
see there's a there's four main
看到有一个有四个主要
components to the course there's
组件 的过程中有
lectures where we go over the high-level
讲座我们去哪里 过高层
concepts recitations where which meet
概念背诵其中符合
once a week for an hour led by a TA and
由一个TA，并导致一小时 ，每周一次
the purpose of the recitations is really
表述的目的是真的
to help you with the labs right so it's
帮助您与实验室右所以它的
very practical and hands-on there's
非常实用和实际操作 存在的
there's seven of those labs and these
还有那些实验室 和这些 七
are really the heart and soul of the
是真正的 心脏和 灵魂
course this is where this is where all
当然，这是哪里，这 是 所有
the real learning comes in I think when
真正的学习进来我认为，当
you actually have to do this stuff and
你确实有做这个东西，
that's why we take the cheating part so
这就是为什么我们采取欺骗一部分 ，所以
seriously because if you do these labs
严重的，因为如果你做这些实验室
you're going to learn an incredible
你要了解一个令人难以置信
amount of really cool stuff if you don't
真的很酷的东西量，如果你不
do them you won't learn anything so each
做这些你就不会学到任何东西 所以每个
one of these these labs is one or two
这些这些实验室中的一个是一个或两个
weeks each and involves typically some
每星期，典型地涉及一些
kind of programming or measurement
一种编程 或测量
there's also two exams a midterm and a
这里还有两个考试 中期和
final the the exams are proctored
最后的考试是监考
they're online proctored in Wien and and
他们 在 网上 维也纳和 监考 和
gates and what we do for the exams is we
盖茨 和 我们为考试做什么是我们
have like we take like four days from
有像我们一样需要时间从4天
10:00 to 10:00 and then you can sign up
10:00至10:00，然后你可以注册
and then we have like multiple clusters
然后我们有 像 多个集群
that are Network isolated and then you
这是 网络隔离，然后你
can sign up for a slot like a 6-hour
可以注册 像6 小时 的槽
slot and the midterm is like nominally
槽和中期 是像名义上
like an hour
就像一个小时
eighty minute exam that's the same exam
80分钟考试这是相同的考试
where you we gave when we used to have
在这里你给我们时，我们曾经有过
people sitting in person so it's
人坐在人因此它的
nominally like 80 minutes but we give
名义上像80分钟但我们给
you like a five or six hour window to do
你喜欢的五 六个小时的窗口 办
it okay so there's so you can sign up
它好了，有那么你可以注册
any time any day that there's a slot
任何时候的任何一天 ， 有一个槽
okay so there's flexibilities that can
好了，有灵活性，可以
kind of tailor it to your your schedule
它 种 定制你的你的日程安排
and we I think we've also removed all
而我们，我认为我们也已经删除所有
the time pressure right so which is you
时间上的压力权利，使这是你
can you can go back you can check your
你可以可以回去了，你可以检查你的
work you can you can just kind of relax
工作，你 可以，你可以只是一种放松
and not not not be worried about
而不是不不 担心
how quickly you do it now there's many
如何迅速您现在就这样做有很多
different ways to get help the main
不同的方式来获得帮助 主
source of information is the course
的信息源是当然
webpage that's a WWF CMU edu Tildy 213
网页这是 一个WWF CMU EDU Tildy 213
and all the information is there we've
所有的信息 是存在的，我们已经
got a complete schedule of lectures and
讲座 得到了一个完整 的时间表，
assignments we don't change it that it's
分配我们不改变它，它的
fixed it so you can look at that and and
固定它 ，你可以看看 这一点，并
plan your semester knowing that those
计划你的学期知道这些
dates of won't change we've actually
的日期不会改变实际上我们
even got all of the lectures posted
即使得到了 所有的讲座发布
ahead of time for for the other
时间提前为其他
instructors around the world who are
世界上谁 是 各地教师
using the book so we needed to get them
使用这本书，所以我们需要 让 他们
all already there's also news at at the
都已经有消息也是在在
very beginning there's sort of news if
最开始有类似的消息，如果
we need to make announcements we'll post
我们需要作出 公告，我们将发布
it there
它有
we don't use either blackboard our
我们不使用任何我们的黑板
Piazza in the course instead we have a
在广场的过程，而不是我们有一个
staff mailing list that you can that you
员工的邮件列表，你可以 说 你
can send mail to if you have questions
可以发送邮件，如果你有任何问题
and all of the TAS and all of the
和所有的TAS和所有的
faculty are subscribed to that staff
教师订阅工作人员
mailing list and so we'll all see it and
邮件列表等，我们都会看到它，
we usually we try to have you know
我们通常我们尝试 让你知道
really fast feedback right so there's so
真快反馈右所以有这么
many people so many people looking at
很多人这么多的人 在 看
your emails that chance is very high
您的电子邮件这样的机会是 非常高的
you'll get an answer back quickly the
你会得到一个答案回来快
disadvantage of having this advantage of
具有这种优点的缺点
this mailing list is that it allows us
这个邮件列表是，它允许 我们
to control the message and control what
控制 消息和控制什么
we're it's what feedback we're giving
我们 这是 我们要提供 的反馈
back to you the disadvantage is that we
回到你的缺点是， 我们
often get the same question over and
经常得到同样的问题在和
over again and so for that we've
一遍 ，所以我们已经
established a FAQ if we find we're
建立了常见问题，如果我们找到我们
getting same questions over and over
一遍又一遍地得到同样的问题
we've established a FAQ on the on the
我们已经建立了一个FAQ上的
course web page for sort of organized by
当然， 网页的排序 举办
labs ok so you can you can see the
实验室确定，所以你可以 你可以看到
answers to frequently asked questions on
经常问到的 问题上
the
该
there we have office hours I think we're
还有 我们的办公时间我认为我们是
still trying to eat we we're still
还在试图吃 我们 我们仍
trying to meet with the staff and figure
努力满足员工和图
out the exact office hours but what I'm
出准确的办公时间，但我什么
what we're thinking now is that we'll
我们现在正在考虑的是，我们会
have office hours so six days a week
有办公时间所以每周六天
okay every day that's Saturday
没关系 ，每天这是星期六
the they will be at the same time in
在他们将在同一时间
same place every day so from 5:45
所以每天从5:45同一个地方
to 8:30 in wean in a queen 5207 cluster
在 断奶 8:30 在女王5207集群
will have 213 TAS there to to help to
将有213个TAS那里帮忙
answer your questions okay so you don't
回答你的问题 好了，你不这样做
have to make appointments I mean you can
要 预约 我的意思是，你 可以
make an appointment to see any staff
预约看不到任何工作人员
member of course but you don't you you
当然成员，但你不知道你你
know that at the same time same place
知道在同一 时间同一地点
every day there's somebody you can go to
每天有一个 你可以去
for help okay for our labs and exams
求助还好我们的实验室和考试
every assignment every lab is a single
每一项 任务每个实验室是单
person so we don't have any group
人，所以我们没有任何组
projects we want you to do the work
项目中，我们要你做的工作
yourself now you know it's important to
自己现在你知道这是非常重要的
work in groups and you will learn how to
在组工作， 你将学会如何
work in groups and other classes see us
在工作组 和其他类的看我们
classes but not NC 13 we want this is a
类，但不是NC 13，我们希望这是一个
kind of a core course we want you to
样的核心，当然，我们希望你能
figure stuff out yourself all of our
数字的东西了自己所有的我们
hand ends will be due at 11:59 p.m. on
手部将于下午11:59 上 是由于
either a Tuesday or Thursday and this is
无论是在周二或周四，这 是
you can see which on the schedule page
你可以看到哪些日程安排页面上
on the course webpage and all of our
在球场上的网页 ， 我们 所有 的
hand ins are using Auto lab where you
手工插件使用Auto实验室，你
know you've probably used it for some of
知道你可能已经用它为一些
your other classes but it's a it's a
你的 其他类，但它是一个这是 一个
Auto grading service that allows you to
自动分级服务，让您
get instant feedback on your on your on
让您在 您的 即时 反馈
your hand in so when you hand it in you
你在这样的手，当 你把它在你
get feedback right away the exams like I
得到 的反馈马上 像我的考试
mentioned are going to be a network
上述将是一个网络
isolated clusters held over multiple
保持在多个分离的簇
days and and you can just sign up for a
天，你可以只 注册一个
slot that's available now what usually
插槽，现已上市，通常是什么
happens is if we offer like the exam
发生的事情是，如果我们 提供像考试
Tuesday Wednesday and Thursday the
周二周三和周四
Thursday slot still up immediately
周四插槽仍有上涨立即
and so you know I guess I should try to
所以你知道，我想我应该尝试
try to sign up soon if you want but
尝试，如果你想尽快注册， 但
people always seem to want to defer to
人们似乎总是要 推迟到
the end rather than and this is me I'd
末尾，而不是，这是我，我会把
want to get it over with but so I just
想 获得它 过去，但所以我只是
thought that is sort of a constraint
以为是那种约束的
right that if you can only sign up for
正确的，如果你只能报名参加
slots that that are available okay now
那现在可还好插槽
you know we make mistakes there's we
你知道，我们犯错有我们
always make mistakes especially with
总是特别配合失误
just so many students so we there's a
只是这么多学生，所以我们有一个
there's a specific process for appealing
有提出上诉的特定进程
grades if you think that there was a
等级，如果你认为有一个
that you're the work wasn't graded
那你的工作没有分级
properly so what you do after after
适当所以你以后后做什么
either an exam or after your labs are
无论是考试或后您的实验室是
graded you have 7 days to file an appeal
分级你有7天 提出上诉
and appeals have to be in in writing and
并呼吁必须以书面和
hardcopy okay so there's no we won't we
纸质好，所以没有 我们不会，我们
won't we won't consider any email any
不会，我们不会考虑 任何电子邮件任何
appeals via email it has to be in
呼吁通过电子邮件它必须是在
writing and hardcopy and you give those
写作和 硬拷贝，你给那些
to me and if I'm not there you can just
对我来说，如果我 不在那里 你可以
slide it under the desk ok and what the
滑动办公桌 OK，什么 下
reason we do it that way is it allows us
我们之所以这样做 的 是它可以让我们
to treat everybody fairly so we get all
公正地对待每一个人，所以我们得到的所有
the appeals together at once and then we
上诉在一起一次，然后我们
can we can we can treat everybody the
可我们可以我们 可以把大家的
same way rather than just sort of doing
同样的方式，而 不是 仅仅几分 做
them one at a time like that ok
他们在一个 类似的确定时间
now for our labs we have ten machines
现在我们的实验室，我们 有几十台
that were donated by Intel called the
该捐赠 英特尔称
shark machines so initially our first
鲨鱼机所以最初我们的第一次
version of t 13 and I guess we started
T第 13 的版本 ， 我想我们开始
using Intel machines in 1999 we used to
使用Intel的机器在1999年，我们用
alpha processors for the first year I
Alpha处理器的第一年， 我
like to fish so all of our machines were
喜欢钓鱼所以我们所有的机器都
they were called the fish machines right
他们被称为鱼机权
they were freshwater fish and then we
他们是淡水鱼，然后我们
upgraded a few years after that and
之后升级了几年，
those were the saltwater fish machines
这些都是在海水鱼机
and then we upgraded like in 2011 to
然后我们升级像在2011年
these Nehalem class servers and run out
这些的Nehalem级服务器 ，并运行了
of fresh water fish and saltwater fish
淡水鱼和咸水鱼
so the next grade up was sharks right so
所以接下来的等级达到了鲨鱼权利，使
every fish is it's named after some kind
每条鱼是它的某种得名
of shark but these are the same machines
鲨鱼，但 这些都是同样的机器
that that you'll that auto lab uses for
那你会是 汽车实验室使用的
grading right so there's some
分级右所以有一些
consistency for performance-oriented
性能为本一致性
labs like malloc lab and you can access
实验室，如malloc的实验室，你可以访问
them that they're you the names are
他们说， 他们是你的名字是
listed on the course webpage and so you
在球场上的网页 ，这样你就上市
can SSH to a specific machine they're
可以ssh来他们是一个特定的机器
all identical if you have an Andrew
如果全部相同，你有安德鲁
account you've already got accounts on
帐户，您已经有账户上
the machines right so there's nothing
机器右侧所以没有什么
special to do or you can just SSH to
专门做或者你可以到SSH
sharp got ICS and it'll just randomly
犀利了ICS， 它会只是随机
put you on on one of the shark machines
把你对鲨鱼的机器之一
okay if if you have any trouble logging
没关系，如果你有任何问题记录
in just send send mail to the staff
在刚刚发送的邮件发送给员工
mailing list okay we know that during
邮件列表好吧，我们知道，在
the semester things come up grandparents
本学期的事情拿出祖父母
died especially near the near the final
尤其是靠近附近死亡的 最后
that's harsh I know but that things come
这是严酷的，但我知道那东西来
up right and you've got your very busy
右上和你有你非常忙
you're taking a lot of courses so
你服用了大量的课程 ，
instead of sort of dealing with requests
而不是那种 处理请求
for extensions and you know all these
为扩展名，你知道所有这些
special cases what we do is we give you
特殊情况下，我们要做的是，我们给你
five Grace days that you can then spend
5 天的宽限期，你可以再花
as you wish so if you hand your work in
如你所愿，所以如果你的手你的工作
late one day late you'll automatically
晚晚一天你会自动
consume a great day okay we don't allow
消耗一个伟大的日子还好我们不允许
you to sort of allocate the grace days
你排序的分配宽限期
you spend one of your grades days by
你花你的成绩的日子之一的
handing in late so if you have a great
在移交晚，所以如果你有一个很好
day less than you hand in late
每天不到你的手在晚
you'll spend that great day but you
你会花那个伟大的日子，但你
won't be penalized for the late hand in
不会受到惩罚的手在后期
and so we have five great days over the
所以我们有 超过五伟大的日子
entire semester and a maximum of two
整个学期 最多两
great days for the assignments now we're
对于分配现在我们伟大的日子
going to set up since the first three
要建立以来的前三个
assignments are kind of not as
分配是一种 不作为
programming intensive and don't take as
编程密集，不为拿
much time we're not going to allow any
很多时候我们不打算 让任何
great days for those because a one grace
对于那些因为一个宽限期伟大的日子
day one sorry one great day and then for
一天一个遗憾一个伟大的日子，然后
the the latter four labs which are much
在后者四个实验室其是多
more intense we're going to allow you to
更激烈，我们要允许你
a max of two great states and the reason
两个伟大的国家和原因的最大
we're doing this is because we don't
我们正在做的，这是因为我们不
want you to burn you're good these great
要你烧你是好这些伟大
days are valuable they're critical
天是有价值的，他们是关键
especially later in the semester when
特别是后来在学期时
have you really really dizzy so we don't
有你真的真的晕了 ，所以我们不
want you to burn off your grace days
要你燃烧掉你的宽限期
early in the semester and this happens
早在学期出现这种情况
every semester and it's and then when
每学期和它的，然后当
alec lab comes up there's no gray space
亚历克实验室出现没有灰色空间
left and it's really it's really sad to
左，它确实是真的伤心地
see that and so we're going to limit you
看到这些 ，所以我们要限制你
to one for those first three just to
一对那些前三刚
help you save you from yourself now
帮助你现在救你脱离自己
it the the the nominal late penalty if
它的标称 点球， 如果
you don't have a great days fifteen
你没有一个伟大的日子15
percent per day and we don't allow any
每天％，而我们不允许 任何
hand in three days after the due date at
手在三天到期日在后
all so that Auto live shuts off the min
这一切都让现场 自动 关断 分钟
and then that's it now if there's some
然后，现在就是这样，如果有一些
kind of catastrophic event you know then
那种灾难性事件，你以后才知道
you know please contact us for an
你知道，请联系我们 的
extension right so we're not you know we
扩展向右所以我们不知道我们
try to be reasonable but most of the
尝试是合理的，但大多数的
most of the most of the reasons that for
大部分的大部分原因，对于
requesting extensions you can handle
扩展请求可以处理
yourself using your grades days and just
自己使用你的 成绩天，只是
I mean this is that this is advice that
我的意思是，这是忠告
give every semester to but I but it's
给每一个学期 ，但我却是
people often don't don't pay attention
人们往往不不注意
but or just they're unable to but but
但或只是他们无法但却
really for every one of these
真正为每一个这些
assignments you want to start early and
分配要提早着手，
the reason is you need to give yourself
原因是，你需要 给 自己
time to to go seek help if you get stuck
时间去寻求帮助，如果你被卡住
because the nature of these very
因为这些很自然
programming intensive assignments like
像编程密集的任务
we have in 213 is that you're going to
我们在 213的是，你要
get stuck and and often it's very hard
卡住，而且往往是 非常困难
to to bound the time you spend on on
对绑定的时候你花上
some of these assignments you know it's
一些任务的，你知道这是
not like problem sets where you can kind
不喜欢的问题集合，其中可以种
of predict you know this will take
的预测您知道这需要
there's no taking like three hours to do
有没有服用像三个小时做
these problem sets for a lot of the 213
这些问题设置了很多213的
assignments it's very difficult to to
分配是对非常困难
sort of manage your time and bound your
排序的管理你的时间和你的约束
time so for that reason you really want
时间这样对你真的那么 想 的 原因
to start early to give yourself a chance
尽早开始给自己一个机会
to get help when you get stuck now in
得到帮助，当你得到 现在卡
the lecture hall of you're permitted to
你报告厅会允许
have your laptop but we ask you not to
有你的笔记本电脑，但 我们要求您不要
send email or instant messaging or cell
发送电子邮件或即时消息或细胞
phone texting or anything like that if
手机短信或类似的东西，如果
you here we want you to to be attentive
你在这里，我们希望你 要细心
and engaged the
并从事了
your presence in lectures and
你的存在讲座 和
recitations is voluntary so we don't
背诵是自愿的，所以我们不
take we don't take role at either of
拿我们没有在 任的 作用，采取
those we encourage you to come but it's
那些我们鼓励你 来了，但它的
not required and no recordings of any
不是必需的 ，没有记录的任何
kind except this one
那种除了这一个
okay the exams and labs are weighted
还好考试和实验室进行加权
equally 50% midterms 20 finals 30 and
同样50％ 期中 20米决赛30和
final grades are based on a straight 90
最终成绩是基于直90
80 70 scale now rough outline of the
的 80 70 现在的规模大致的轮廓
semester the first three labs cover
学期前三个实验室 覆盖
programs reference the Machine
节目引用 机
representations of programs and data
的程序和数据表示
data lab is how we teach you about fit
数据实验室是如何教你 适合
level representations of data so you'll
数据的层次表示，所以你
sell collection of puzzles and see like
卖拼图的收集和看到像
a puzzle might be is a little function
一个谜可能是一个小功能
that you have to implement and like
你必须 实现和像
absolute value so a function that
绝对值这样一个函数，
returns the absolute value of its art
返回其 艺术 的绝对值
input argument the kicker is that we
输入参数踢球是我们
restrict the set of operators that you
限制集合运算的你
can use and it has to be straight line
可以使用，它必须 是直线
code no conditionals or loops and so to
代码没有条件语句或循环 等来
solve these puzzles so imagine how you
解决这些难题，从而想象有你
might try to solve absolute value
不妨尝试解决绝对值
without using an if statement right the
不使用if语句权利
normal way to do it would be if X less
正常的方式来做到这一点 是，如果X少
than zero return x or negative x
大于 零 的回报 x或负x
see I told you we make mistakes but
看到我告诉你，我们会犯错误，但
imagine how you might do that without
想象一下，你会如何做， 没有
using conditionals and only using bit
使用条件语句，只使用 位
level C operations right so this is how
C级经营权，所以 这 是 怎么
this is how this is our way of teaching
这是怎么了，这是 我们的教学方式
you how data is really represented in
你的数据是如何真正代表了
the machine now the bomb lab which
现在该机的 炸弹实验室，其
you've probably heard at this is this is
你可能听说过 这是，这是
a kind of famous all over the world now
一种著名的世界 各地的现
and at CMU the bomb lab is the way we
在CMU 炸弹实验室是我们的方式
teach you how to read and understand
教你如何阅读和理解
assembly language and a bomb just
汇编语言和炸弹只是
briefly a bomb is a is a C program that
简要地炸弹是一个是一个C程序
consists of a collection of six phases
包括六个阶段的集合
and each phase wants you to type
每个阶段要你输入
something in at the keyboard if you type
东西在，如果你键入键盘
in the what it wants you to type what it
在它要你输入什么
expects you to type then you've diffused
希望你键入，那么你已经扩散
that phase and it goes to the next phase
这个阶段并进入下一个阶段
then you have to type with that phase
那么你必须与相输入
once and if you defuse all the phases
一次，如果你化解所有的 阶段
then you've diffused the bomb however if
那么你已经 但是如果扩散炸弹
you type in the wrong thing then the
你在错误的东西类型，然后在
bomb explodes by printing boom and you
炸弹爆炸的印刷繁荣和 你
have to try it again and the kicker is
必须再次尝试和踢球的是
in either case when if you explode the
在这两种情况下，当你爆
bomb or defuse a phase that information
炸弹化解相位信息
gets sent to auto lab if you and we use
被发送到汽车实验室，如果你和我们使用
the defusing string that that your bomb
在化解字符串，你的炸弹
sends us and we check it out on a copy
发送我们，我们检查出来的一个副本
of your bomb that we keep on the server
你弹的是我们在服务器上保留
that's another thing every everybody
那是另一件事大家每
gets a different bomb slightly different
得到了不同的炸弹略有不同
bomb so we check so when you defuse when
炸弹所以我们检查，所以当你缓和 当
you just use the phase Auto lab takes
你只需要使用相自耦实验室将
the string that it that your bomb sends
它是你的炸弹发送字符串
us and then compares against the local
我们然后比较针对本地
copy of your bomb if you explode phase
你弹的副本，如果你爆炸 阶段
you lose half a point so there's a real
你失去了半个百分点所以有一个真正的
consequence to exploding a bomb it's
后果爆炸炸弹它
very very tense
非常非常紧张
until you learn how to use GDB to set a
直到你学会如何使用GDB设置
breakpoint before the function that
该功能之前， 该断点
sends the information to the server and
信息发送到 服务器，
we want you to do that right so a bombs
我们要你做 的是 正确的这么炸弹
are really the bombs really beautiful
真的炸弹 真的很美
it's kind of fun it's kind of like a
它是一种乐趣它有点像一
video game it it teaches you how to read
视频游戏它 它教你 如何看
compiler generated code because the only
编译器生成的代码，因为只有
oh the kicker is sorry the kicker is we
哦起脚 对不起踢球的是我们
don't give you the source code all we
不给你的源 代码，我们都
give you is the binary hence the binary
给你的是二进制，因此二进制
bomb so in order to defuse a bomb you've
炸弹所以为了化解 你已经 炸弹
got to fire up gdb single trace through
拨通了火了GDB单跟踪
the find where the code is for each
查找其中的代码是 每个
phase single trace through that code and
通过该代码相单跟踪和
sort of reverse engineer and figure out
排序的反向工程，并找出
what it wants you to type in and then
它要你 输入 ，然后
you'll quickly find out where that
你会很快找出 那
function that explodes the bomb is and
该爆炸炸弹的功能是和
you'll put a breakpoint there and so we
你会放一个断点，所以我们
want you to do that because the bomb
要你做，因为炸弹
besides teaching you how to program
除了教你如何编程
assembly language it also teaches you
汇编语言也教 你
sort of organically how to use gdb
排序的有机如何使用GDB
because you really can't do it if you
因为你真的不能，如果你这样做
don't use if you don't run gdb and then
如果你不运行GDB，然后不要使用
the the third lab is this is a new lab
在第三个实验是，这 是一个新的实验室
the semester the Randy's developed
兰迪的开发 学期
called the attack lab and we developed
所谓攻击实验室，并且开发
this lab specifically for 64-bit
本实验中专门为64位
architecture so this is a reflection of
架构所以这是一个反射
the change from 32 bits to 64 bits and
从32位到64位的变化和
this is really excited about this one
这是非常兴奋这一个
you'll learn how to you'll learn how to
您将学习如何您将学习如何
write exploits using return to a sort of
编写使用回攻击了几分
a modern technique called return to
一个名为回到现代技术
return oriented programming which is
返回导向编程这是
kind of the modern modern way that
一种现代的现代方式
hackers deal with the fact that stacks
黑客对付这堆事实
in newer machines move around and and
在较新的机器走动，和
are prohibitive and make an impossible
而怯步 ，使不可能
to execute code on the on the stack so
到堆栈上的执行代码，以便
this the brand new labs really I think
这个全新的实验室，我真的觉得
it's really going to be really going to
它真的是 真的要
be neat
整洁
in the memory hierarchy when we study
在我们研究的存储层次
the memory hierarchy we we have a cash
存储器层次我们，我们有一个现金
lab called the cash lab where you'll
实验室称为现金实验室在那里你会
build your own cash simulator so this is
建立你自己的现金 模拟器，所以这是
how you sort of learn how this hardware
你怎么样的学习这怎么硬件
that Randy was mentioning called it
兰迪刚提称它为
cache memory works you'll build a
高速缓存存储器的工作，你将构建一个
simulator and see for that and then
模拟器和 查看该 再
you'll take a small transpose function
你会拿一个小转功能
and you'll try to make that that code
你会尝试 作出这样的代码
run with as few misses as possible on
用尽可能少遗漏地运行
your simulator and this will involve
你的模拟器，这将涉及
sort of understanding of how the memory
排序如何记忆的理解
hierarchy works and how to exploit it
层次结构的工作原理，以及如何利用它
the part of the course where you we sort
在那里你，我们的排序过程的一部分
of transitioned from hardware to
从硬件转移到
interacting with the the system software
与 系统 软件进行交互
that the operating system there's sort
该操作系统有排序
of a concept that we call exceptional
我们称之为特殊的一个概念
control flaws that exists in all parts
存在于所有部分控制缺陷
of the system and it sort of represents
该系统和IT类的代表
that intellectual transition from
从知识转化
hardware to software so this is how this
硬件到软件 ，所以这是如何
was sort of a key idea that allowed us
是那种使我们 的一个关键理念
to kind of smoothly move from from
来样顺利 从移动
hardware to software in some
硬件在某些软件
intellectually consistent way and so the
智力一致的方式等等
the ideas that you cover an exceptional
你掩盖一个特殊 的 想法
control floor like low hard low-level
控制楼，如低硬低水平
hardware interrupts and exceptions and
硬件中断 和异常和
then at the higher level sort of
然后在水平排序的更高
involving hardware and operating system
涉及到硬件和操作系统
software is the idea of an opera of the
软件的歌剧的想法
process context switch ok so this is
进程上下文切换 确定，所以这 是
this is where you start to learn what
这是你开始学习什么
processes are and how to how to ask the
过程是如何如何提出
kernel to create in manage processes for
内核创建管理 流程，
you at the next higher level or a
你在一级或
software form of exceptional control
特殊控制的软件形式
flow called a signal so this exists
流称为信号所以这存在
solely on the Linux kernel and then and
单就Linux 内核 ，然后和
then even at a higher level at there's
那么即使在较高的 水平，在有
an application C language version of
的应用C 语言版
exceptional control flow call set jump
异常控制流调用集跳
and long jump so this this notion of
和跳远所以这本概念
exceptional control flow kind of exists
异常控制流样 的存在
in all parts of the system we covered
在系统的各个部分，我们讨论
all at once
一次全部
and the lab that we use to sort of
而我们使用的实验室进行排序
exercise all these ideas is called the
行使所有这些想法 被称为
shell lab and in the shell lab you'll
外壳实验室和外壳实验中，您会
write your own linux shell which is
写自己的 Linux外壳是
really cool so that's the program the
真的很酷所以这是 该程序的
command line program that you interact
你互动命令行程序
with whenever you log into a Linux box
与当你登录到Linux中
you're going to write your own and I
你会写自己 和我
don't look for me that was really
别看我是真的
exciting when I could like write
令人兴奋的，当 我喜欢写
something that looked like a real shell
东西看起来像一个真正的壳
it was pretty neat the next area is well
这是非常整齐 的下一个 领域是很好
study is called virtual memory virtual
研究称为虚拟内存虚拟
memory is a sort of combination of
存储器 是一种的组合的
hardware and software that presents an
硬件和软件 提供了一个
abstraction to you of this variant of
抽象，你这个变种的
memory is a very large array of bytes
存储器是一个非常大的阵列的字节
when in reality memory is a hierarchy of
在现实内存时的层次结构
hardware and of cache memories and D
硬件和高速缓冲存储器和D
Rams virtual memory provides a very
公羊虚拟内存提供了一个非常
high-level abstraction and as just a
高层次的抽象，只是一个
linear sequence of bytes it also does
它也确实字节线性序列
provide a lot of a lot of other useful
提供很多很多 其他有用的
abstractions that make many different
抽象，使许多不同
parts of the system much easier to
该系统的部分 更容易
manage
管理
ok so we'll learn we learn about virtual
好了，所以我们要学习，我们 了解虚拟
memory we'll learn how it works we'll
内存我们将了解 它是 如何 工作，我们将
learn about the performance impact
了解性能的影响
potential performance impact that it has
潜在的性能影响，它有
on your programs and and we'll also
在您的程序和我们也将
learn how to manage that large pool of
学习如何管理的大型游泳池
memory that it makes available to you
内存， 它提供给您
and the lab that we do that the lab
和实验室，我们做实验室
where you'll do that is called malloc
在那里你会做那个叫的malloc
lab and in the malloc lab you'll write
实验室和实验室中的malloc，你会写
your own malloc and free functions ok so
你自己的malloc和free 函数 确定，所以
you'll you'll reinvent the functionality
你会，你会重塑功能
of the Lib C malloc and free and this is
该 库ç的malloc和free，这 是
a maybe a minute maybe it's two pages of
一个也许一分钟，也许是两页
code but it'll be a guarantee it'll be
代码，但它会是一个保证这将是
the most sophisticated difficult two
最复杂的困难2
pages of code you've written not only
的代码页你不仅写
because since it's managing the memory
因为既然它是管理内存
system you can't use all of I mean C
你不能使用所有的I系统均值C
doesn't have many C doesn't help you out
没有多少 C不 帮你解决
a lot
很多
with extractions for data structures but
用提取的数据结构，但
when you're writing but at least it does
当你写，但至少它
give you ideas like strux unions that
给你喜欢STRUX 工会的想法，
you can use to structure your memory
你可以用它来构建你的记忆
when you're writing a malloc package you
当你写一个malloc包你
can't use any of those you have to ride
不能使用任何这些，你必须 骑
exclusively on pointers and casting
专门对指针和铸造
because you malloc tax is working at
因为你的malloc税在工作
such a low level and so it's a very very
如此低的水平，所以这是一个非常非常
difficult piece of code for that reason
困难的一段代码出于 这一原因
but also the design space for malloc is
同时也 为malloc的设计空间
is enormous you have many options
是巨大的，你有很多选择
they all have implications that
它们都具有影响的是
trade-off performance and a memory
权衡性能和内存
efficiency and finally in the last part
效率，终于在最后 一部分
of the course we deal with i/o
过程中， 我们处理的I / O
input/output so so far in the course
输入/输出所以在使用过程迄今
we've just talked about sort of running
我们刚刚谈到的排序运行
programs on machines in the last part of
在最后一部分的机器上的程序
the course we'll talk about input and
过程中，我们将讨论输入和
output sending data into and out of the
输出发送数据移入和移出的
machine so we'll look at basic concepts
机，所以我们来看看基本概念
of Linux i/o will and since I think the
Linux的的I / O将因为我 觉得
most interesting form of i/o is is
我的最有趣的形式/ O是被
networking which allows you to talk to
网络，让你去跟
machines anywhere in the world
机器 在世界任何地方
using the internet we'll also talk we'll
利用互联网，我们还将 讨论 我们将
learn how to do network programming
学习如何做网络编程
you'll learn how to write programs that
您将学习如何编写 程序
use the sockets interface which is the
使用套接字接口这 是
basic interface for the Internet to talk
基本接口，用于互联网 通话
to machines any potentially any machine
到机器的任何潜在的任何机
in the in the world and that's really
在世界上 ，这就是真正的
exciting I mean once I can still
令人兴奋的我的意思是，一旦我仍然可以
remember when developing this course I
记得开发这个 当然，我 当
had two windows open on my machine
有两个窗口在我的机器上打开
I was SSH into two different machines
我SSH 到两台不同的 机器
and I wrote a program to send a message
我写了一个程序来发送消息
like hello world from one machine to the
喜欢的Hello World从一台机器到
other and when that hello world appeared
其他 和当 世界你好出现
on the second windows like so exciting I
在第二窗口，像这样 令人兴奋的 我
mean if you're a nerd it's really
意思是，如果你是一个书呆子它真的
exciting but
令人兴奋，但
but just the thought that that could
只是一想到可能
have been at any machine right that
一直在任何机器正确的
could have been any machine that does
本来，做任何机器
just like opens up a whole new world
就像打开了一个全新的世界
okay all of our all of our hands are
还好 我们 所有 的一切 我们手中 的 是
using a system called Auto lab which was
使用一种称为自动实验室这是系统
developed here and you can access it if
在这里开发的， 如果 你能访问 它
you if you are on the roster as of this
你，如果你是在名册的本
morning if you go to the Auto lab link
早晨，如果你去自动实验室链接
then you'll see this course was based on
然后你会看到这当然是基于
your page if you're not enrolled you
你的页面，如果你 不录取 你
won't have an auto lab account and you
不会有一个自动的实验室帐户 和你
have to be enrolled to get an auto lab
已经被招收得到一个自动实验室
account so if you if you want to try to
帐户所以如果你，如果你想尝试
wait it out and wait for people to drop
等待了 ，等待的人 砸
I'll make the first couple of elite the
我会做的第一对夫妇 精英 的
first assignment due available from the
由于可以从第一个任务
course web page so you can work on it
当然网页，这样你就可以在它的工作
without actually handing into Auto lab
没有 实际移交 到汽车实验室
but at least you can keep going okay if
但至少你可以，如果继续下去好吗
you enroll actually I didn't update this
你居然招收我没有更新此
but I updated the Auto lab accounts
但我更新了 汽车实验室账户
today now one final thing if you have
如果你有今天现在还有最后一件事
waitlist questions please don't don't
候补名单问题，请不要做不
send email to the staff because we don't
发送电子邮件给员工，因为 我们不
control the waiver so you should contact
控制 减免，所以你应该联系
one of these either Cathy Catherine or
这些中的一个或者凯西凯瑟琳或
Zahra depending on which class you had
扎赫拉取决于哪个类，你有
okay so that's that welcome again
好了，就是这样再次欢迎
looking forward to a great semester and
期待着一个伟大的学期
we'll see you on Thursday
我们会看到你在星期四